

My Contact

shahnawaz.1504ali@gmail.co

© m 7289020186, 9990838084



Hard Skill

- Software skills Python, Django, SQL, HTML,CSS, JavaScript(Basics) and Bootstrap
- Database RDBMS- MYSQL
- Tools Figma UI, Github

Soft Skill

- Observation
- Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking

Education Background

- Bachelor of Engineering (ECE)
 Rungta College of Engineering C.S.V.T.U
 (Chhattishgarh)CGPA 73.65
- H.S.S (12th) Physics, Chemistry, Maths, English, Physical Education
 S.S.D Sarswati Bal Mandir (CBSE) - New
 Delhi, India CGPA - 77.4
- S.S.C (10th) Science, Maths, Social Science, Hindi, English, Sanskrit
 S.S.D Saraswati Bal Mandir (CBSE) - New Delhi, India
 CGPA - 80.1

Md Shahnawaz Ali

Python Developer

About Me

High-energy software developer with having B.E in ECE and prepared to contribute abilities to a software engineering role while further developing acquired skills and gaining real-world experience. Positively impact operations with top-notch communication and critical thinking skills. Highly organized, responsible, and well-versed in Full stack development using Django stack and JS. And excellent understanding of Python,database and SQL.

Professional Experience

Working in ABL Education LLP as Pythor Developer 08-Sep-2022 -- Present Key responsibilities:

- Build and maintain the mechanisms that process data and perform an action on websites.
- Actively participated in Agile methodologies, contributing to sprint planning and daily stand-ups.
- Write high-quality code to produce a sustainable web application.
- Prepared API documentation with Postman and conducted knowledge transfer sessions.

Bhaskar Instructive Impetus Pvt Ltd as Associate Developer 20-Nov-2019 to 31-Aug-2022.

Key responsibilities:

- Seek new information and creative new approaches to frequently develop, learn, and present a variety of content from technology and engineering design processes
- participates or initiates the testing process and discusses test results with the senior developer to alter or modify the current features and specifications.

Thinklabs Technosolution Pvt Ltd as STEM Innovation Engineer 29-oct-2018 to 15-Nov-2019

Key responsibilities:

- Facilitating student learning and overseeing hands-on learning.
- Develop projects based on Computer Vision and Image processing.
- Conducted research to assist with routine tasks and special projects.
- Reviewed and strengthened program operations through continuous assessments of operational plans and strategies.

Robotech Pvt Ltd as STEM Innovation Engineer 15-June-2017 to 27-Oct-2018.

Key responsibilities:

- Developed strong expertise in the field of Microcontroller, Robotics and IoT-based sensors.
- Developed curriculum for Robotics, Coding, and IoT for schools and college students.
- Provide training to all the STEM Educators on different platforms.
 Identified issues, analyzed problems, and provided solutions to problems.